<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CS111 - Adventures of programming</title><link>https://vikaspatelp83.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on CS111 - Adventures of programming</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 01:24:39 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vikaspatelp83.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Avoid Memory Leaks While Coding in C Plus Plus</title><link>https://vikaspatelp83.github.io/post/avoid-memory-leaks-while-coding-in-c-plus-plus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 01:24:39 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://vikaspatelp83.github.io/post/avoid-memory-leaks-while-coding-in-c-plus-plus/</guid><description>Instructions
Things You&amp;rsquo;ll Need
Proficiency in C++ C++ compiler Debugger and other investigative software tools Part 1 Understand the operator basics. The C++ operator new allocates heap memory. The delete operator frees heap memory. For every new, you should use a delete so that you free the same memory you allocated:
1 2 3 char* str = new char [30]; // Allocate 30 bytes to house a string.</description></item><item><title>Operators in Bash Shell Programming</title><link>https://vikaspatelp83.github.io/post/operators-in-bash-shell-programming/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 01:16:10 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://vikaspatelp83.github.io/post/operators-in-bash-shell-programming/</guid><description>Photo by NASA on Unsplash
If you want to learn bash bash scripting please read this article.
Learn complete Linux bash (shell) scripting in one article
Operators help us perform various types of operations such as addition, multiplication etc.
There are following types of operators present in bash:
Arithmetic, Relational, Boolean, File Test, String Test 1. Arithmetic Operators All the arithmetic operators present in bash are discussed below with examples.</description></item><item><title>Learn Complete Linux Bash Scripting in One Article</title><link>https://vikaspatelp83.github.io/post/learn-complete-linux-bash-scripting-in-one-article/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:59:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://vikaspatelp83.github.io/post/learn-complete-linux-bash-scripting-in-one-article/</guid><description>&amp;ndash; Photo by Iván Rivero from Pexels
In this article I&amp;rsquo;ll be discussing about linux bash scripting (shell scripting) and I will cover every fundamental concept that you need to get started with bash scripting under linux environment.
Bash scripting is a critical skill for every programmer.
First of all you will need a linux machine to execute these scripts.
You can use any of the below techniques to get a linux machine:</description></item><item><title>Access Wsl Filesystem From Windows 10 File Explorer</title><link>https://vikaspatelp83.github.io/post/access-wsl-filesystem-from-windows-10-file-explorer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:52:26 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://vikaspatelp83.github.io/post/access-wsl-filesystem-from-windows-10-file-explorer/</guid><description>If you want to get Linux environment in your Windows system there are some solutions that provide the oportunity.
For example MYSYS, CYGWIN and a Virtual Machine (If you want complete linux machine) or Multiple Boot.
But some of them aren&amp;rsquo;t much powerful and some are resources hungry like Virtual Machine.
So, the solution is WSL (Windows Subsystem for Linux).
You can learn how to setup WSL from here.
In this article I&amp;rsquo;ll be sharing how to access WSL file system from Windows 10 file explorer.</description></item></channel></rss>